Roger Borrup Papers 1984.0023
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Roger Borrup Papers
undated, 1933-1986
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1984.0023
6 Linear Feet
Born in 1913 in Plainville, New Jersey, Roger Borrup worked for the Hartford Times as a printer and typesetter for 44 years until his retirement in 1975. A long-time member of the Hartford Typographical Union, No. 127, Borrup was also the co-founder, incorporator and trustee of the Connecticut Electric Railway Association. Roger Borrup died 9 September 1987 at the age of 74.
Access
The collection is open and available for research with the exception of Grievance materials (restricted until 2054). An exception to the restriction is possible if no personally identifiable information is present in the materials.
Acquisition Information
The papers were transferred by the University of Connecticut Foundation in 1985.
Arrangement
Series I: Hartford Typographical Union (undated, 1933-1978).
Series II: Periodicals (1951-1986).
Series III: Railways (1985).
Biography
Born in 1913 in Plainville, New Jersey, Roger Borrup worked for the Hartford Times as a printer and typesetter for 44 years until his retirement in 1975. A long-time member of the Hartford Typographical Union, No. 127, and completed many of the Union training programs. Borrup became the first secretary of the Hartford Typographical Union before its merger with the Central Connecticut Typographical Union.
Borrup was also the co-founder, incorporator and trustee of the Connecticut Electric Railway Association, Inc., which operates the Warehouse Point Trolley Museum in East Windsor, CT. For more than 50 years he was a member of the National Railway Historical Society, the Seashore Trolley Museum, the Mystic Valley Railway Society and the Railroad Enthusiasts, Inc. His interest in railway travel extended to the editing and publishing of over 80 transportation bulletins, the first having been printed in 1940.
Roger Borrup died 9 September 1987 at the age of 74.
The Hartford Typographical Union, No. 127 was organized in 1864. It represented workers in the areas of design, composition mechanical, color separation, photography, stripping, platemaking, and printing. The Hartford Typographical Union merged with the Central Connecticut Typographical Union>, No. 679, in 1977.
Custodial History
The papers were donated to the University of Connecticut Foundation on 1 March 1985.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of Union related training manuals, instructions, tests, certificates and rule books in addition to a Hartford Typographical Union type set. The papers also include legal records and publications for the Union, periodicals and a small collection of materials relating to railway travel. The bulk of the materials date from the late 1960s through the late 1970s.
Financial Records; Legal documents; Publications (documents); Administrative records; Reports; Correspondence
- Series I: Hartford Typographical Union, undated, 1933 - 1978
  - Subseries A: Personal File, undated
    - ITU tests, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - ITU lessons in printing, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Certificates, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - ITU rule books, undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Training manuals, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Instructions, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Printing type, undated
    - Type (Box 1)
  - Subseries C: Secretary's Records, 1933 - 1978
    - Account book—dues, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Address lists, 1971-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 9-10)
    - Agreement--Hartford Typographical Union and Hartford Times, 1974-1975 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - Appeals—Hearings and arbitrations, 1962-1970 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Connecticut State Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1975-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Contracts and Bylaws (Box 1:, Folder 14)
      - Hartford Times, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
      - Ace, Wolf and Bond Printing (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence
      - Copies, 1975-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
      - Hartford Times, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
      - ITU, 1976-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
      - New England Allied Printing Trades Association, undated (Box 1:, Folder 19)
      - New England Conference of Typographical Unions, 1975-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
      - Union Labor Life Insurance Company, 1969-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Employer Contribution Returns, 1972-1976 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Executive Board Appeals, 1964-1965 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - ITU
      - Affiliation News Bulletin, undated (Box 1:, Folder 24)
      - Book of Laws, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
      - Contract Sample, undated (Box 1:, Folder 26)
      - Documents, undated (Box 1:, Folder 27)
      - Negotiation Newsletter, undated (Box 1:, Folder 28)
      - Negotiated Pension plan revision, 1971, 1974 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
      - Newsletters, undated (Box 1:, Folder 30)
      - Secretary's manual, 1975, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
      - Traveling cards, 1966-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Local Voting and Ballots, 1972-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - Membership dues cards, undated (Box 1:, Folder 34)
    - Meeting notices, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - Meeting notices and minutes, 1965-1977 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - Mortuary Benefit applications, 1975-1978 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - Negotiated pension plan receipts, undated (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - Negotiating Committee reports, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - Passbook
      - State Savings Bank, 1962 (Box 2:, Folder 40)
      - Travelers Bank and Trust Company, 1933-1943 (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - Pension roll reports, 1974-1976 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - Registration numbers Local 127, undated (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - Remittance Statements to ITU, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
- Series II: Periodicals, 1951 - 1986
  - 44th Annual Conference of New England Typographical Unions, 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
  - ITU Review
    - v. 27, #10, 1984 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - v. 28, #3-4, 6-9, 12, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - v. 29, #1-4, 6-9, 1986 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - The Typographical Journal
    - v. 118-119, 1951 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
    - v. 120-121, 1952 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    - v. 122-123, 1953 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - v. 124-125, 1954 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
    - v. 126-127, 1955 (Box 2:, Folder 53)
    - v. 128, #2, 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 54)
    - v. 130-131, 1957 (Box 2:, Folder 55)
    - v. 132-133, 1958 (Box 3:, Folder 56)
    - v. 134-135, 1959 (Box 3:, Folder 57)
    - v. 136, #3, 5, 6, 1960 (Box 3:, Folder 58)
    - v. 137, #1-5, 1960 (Box 3:, Folder 59)
    - v. 138, #1-6, 1961 (Box 3:, Folder 60)
    - v. 139, #1-6, 1961 (Box 3:, Folder 61)
    - v. 140, #1-4, 6, 1962 (Box 3:, Folder 62)
    - v. 141, #1-6, 1962 (Box 3:, Folder 63)
    - v. 142, 1963 January, March - July (Box 3:, Folder 64)
    - v. 144-145, 1964 (Box 3:, Folder 65)
    - v. 146-147, 1965 (Box 3:, Folder 66)
    - v. 148, 1966 February - April, June - December (Box 3:, Folder 67)
    - v. 150, 1967 January (Box 3:, Folder 68)
    - v. 154, 1969 February (Box 3:, Folder 69)
    - v. 184, 1984 June, October, December (Box 3:, Folder 70)
    - v. 186, 1985 June - October (Box 3:, Folder 71)
    - v. 188, 1986 January - May, July - September (Box 3:, Folder 72)
- Series III: Railways, undated, 1985
  - Connecticut Electric Railway, undated (Box 3:, Folder 73)
  - Connecticut...Helicopter portraits, undated (Box 3:, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3:, Folder 75)
  - Interstate Street Railway, undated (Box 3:, Folder 76)
  - Transportation Bulletin, #77, undated (Box 3:, Folder 77)
  - Trolleygrams, v. 3A, #1, undated (Box 3:, Folder 78)
  - Trolley Days in Connecticut
    - v. 1, #1-4, undated (Box 3:, Folder 79)
    - v. 2, #1-3, undated (Box 3:, Folder 80)
    - v. 3, #1-4, undated (Box 3:, Folder 81)
  - Trolley Days in Florida, #1, 1985 (Box 3:, Folder 82)
  - Trolley Days in Vermont, v. 1 #1, undated (Box 3:, Folder 83)
  - Trolley Days in Western Massachusetts, v. 1 #2-3, undated (Box 3:, Folder 84)